hello everyone
welcome back again with us on
another episode at Military TV
in today's session
we will take a deep look on the process of
how does a submarine fire a torpedo
I bet not many people know how it works do you  so
if you are curious to the answer
stay tuned with us and watch the video till the end
torpedo
a self propelled underwater weapon designed to
launch above or below the water's surface
is equipped with an explosive warhead
it can detonate or contact with or
in proximity to the targets
this underwater projectile has been used strictly
from the 19th century for the battleship and used to
give a great effect during the World War I
interesting it experiences some constant changes and
refinement allowing for modern ones with light weights
as well as straight running automated homers or wire
guided and can be launched from a variety of platforms
important before the launching process the torpedo is
located at a torpedo tube it's like a cylinder shaped
device and installed aboard surface vessels
deck mounted torpedo launchers are usually built for a
specific type of torpedo while submarine torpedo tubes
are general purpose launchers and are often capable of
discharging mines and cruise missiles too
in the following scene we would like to precisely
illustrate exactly how the torpedo launching system
works
so the first important thing is to assure that the
locking lugs are in the right configuration to avoid
the torpedo sliding forward and backward
the forward locking lug is in the load position
while the back one is in the up position
then the breach door is opened to slide the torpedo in
additionally this can also be
done by using hydraulic system
when the torpedo is moved against
the locking lug in the tube
the locking lug comes down and secures the torpedo
and the breach door is closed and locked
the torpedo is now stably located
in the tube and ready to fire
unfortunately it is not the time yet
there are actually some
sequences that need to take place  first
the tube has to be flooded
started by opening a valve to allow water to flood
the container called water round torpedo WRT tank
then the valve up top needs to be opened too in order
to release the air as it is filled up with water
as the torpedo tube is being filled
with water from the WTR tank
it definitely goes up to the vent line
at the top there is electrode
that senses the seawater
at this phase the valve on top and on bottom close
and the torpedo as the tube is filled with water
however
the problem is that there is a lower pressure
inside the boat compared to the outside
as generally known that the deeper a
submarine goes the higher pressure it has  therefore
the most crucial thing to do
is to equalize the system
this function is performed by equalizing valve
when this thing is turned
the pressure inside the tube will now
be equal to that outside the ocean
at the same time it is important to relocate the
slide valve at this time the slide valve also needs
to be moved slide valve refers to a movable
section of the tube about halfway down the torpedo
that circularly covers all of the several
rectangular pores through which water can enter
then the water can be dumped into torpedo tube
at this point the torpedo is completely ready to fire
when the fire instruction comes from the control
room both the locking lugs retract allowing the
torpedo to move longitudinally and pressurized
water from an impulse tank to provide a massive
amount of pressure through which will then be
introduced into the torpedo tube through all the
rectangular holes covered by the slide valve
this extra water forces the torpedo
out of the front of the submarine
to conclude
a torpedo launch of the naval warfare seems
to be the least visible aspect to show
since the nature of submarine warfare means that
none ever witnessed the torpedo tube mechanism and
how the torpedo is pushed from its tube
this is because the submarine's crew is on the
other side of a pressurized hull and unable
to follow the chain of events after loading
the torpedo and ordering the launch
it's lucky that we watch this video today
and know exactly how it works now
that's all for today
see you next time